{
  "nodes": [
    {
      "content": "Windows PowerShell User&amp;#39;s Guide",
      "pos": [
        11,
        46
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows PowerShell User&amp;#39;s Guide",
      "pos": [
        181,
        216
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Windows PowerShell is a command\\-line shell and scripting environment that brings the power of the .NET Framework to command\\-line users and script writers.",
      "pos": [
        217,
        373
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "It introduces a number of powerful new concepts that enables you to extend the knowledge you have gained and the scripts you have created within the Windows Command Prompt and Windows Script Host environments.",
      "pos": [
        374,
        583
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Audience",
      "pos": [
        588,
        596
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "The Windows PowerShell User's Guide is intended for IT professionals, programmers, and power users who have no prior background with Windows PowerShell.",
      "pos": [
        597,
        749
      ]
    },
    {
      "content": "Although backgrounds in scripting and Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI) are helpful, they are not assumed or required to understand this document.",
      "pos": [
        750,
        903
      ]
    }
  ],
  "content": "---\ntitle: Windows PowerShell User&#39;s Guide\nms.custom: na\nms.reviewer: na\nms.suite: na\nms.tgt_pltfrm: na\nms.topic: article\nms.assetid: f5fdcca2-0c7c-4450-8883-31576107d435\n---\n# Windows PowerShell User&#39;s Guide\nWindows PowerShell is a command\\-line shell and scripting environment that brings the power of the .NET Framework to command\\-line users and script writers. It introduces a number of powerful new concepts that enables you to extend the knowledge you have gained and the scripts you have created within the Windows Command Prompt and Windows Script Host environments.\n\n## Audience\nThe Windows PowerShell User's Guide is intended for IT professionals, programmers, and power users who have no prior background with Windows PowerShell. Although backgrounds in scripting and Windows Management Instrumentation (WMI) are helpful, they are not assumed or required to understand this document.\n\n"
}