{"nodes":[{"content":"Writing help for DSC configurations","pos":[2,37]},{"content":"Applies To: Windows Windows PowerShell 5.0","pos":[40,82]},{"content":"You can use comment-based help in DSC configurations.","pos":[84,137]},{"content":"Users can access the help by calling the configuration function with <ph id=\"ph1\">`-?`</ph>, or by using the","pos":[138,228]},{"content":"<bpt id=\"p1\">[</bpt>Get-Help<ept id=\"p1\">](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hh849696.aspx)</ept> cmdlet.","pos":[230,307]},{"content":"For more information about PowerShell comment-based help, see","pos":[308,369]},{"content":"about_Comment_Based_Help","pos":[372,396]},{"content":"The following example shows a script that contains two configurations and comment-based help for each configuration:","pos":[459,575]},{"content":"Viewing configuration help","pos":[2216,2242]},{"content":"To view the help for a configuration, use the <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-Help<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept> cmdlet with the name of the function, or type the name of the function followed by <ph id=\"ph1\">`-?`</ph>.","pos":[2244,2391]},{"content":"The following is the output","pos":[2392,2419]},{"content":"of the previous function when passed to <bpt id=\"p1\">**</bpt>Get-Help<ept id=\"p1\">**</ept>:","pos":[2420,2473]},{"content":"See Also","pos":[3256,3264]},{"content":"DSC Configurations","pos":[3268,3286]}],"content":"# Writing help for DSC configurations\n\n>Applies To: Windows Windows PowerShell 5.0\n\nYou can use comment-based help in DSC configurations. Users can access the help by calling the configuration function with `-?`, or by using the \n[Get-Help](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hh849696.aspx) cmdlet. For more information about PowerShell comment-based help, see \n[about_Comment_Based_Help](https://technet.microsoft.com/en-us/library/hh847834.aspx).\n\nThe following example shows a script that contains two configurations and comment-based help for each configuration:\n\n```powershell\n<#\n.SYNOPSIS\nA brief description of the function or script. This keyword can be used only once for each configuration.\n\n\n.DESCRIPTION\nA detailed description of the function or script. This keyword can be used only once for each configuration.\n\n\n.PARAMETER computername\nThe description of a parameter. Add a .PARAMETER keyword for each parameter in the function or script syntax.\n\nType the parameter name on the same line as the .PARAMETER keyword. Type the parameter description on the lines following the .PARAMETER keyword. \nWindows PowerShell interprets all text between the .PARAMETER line and the next keyword or the end of the comment block as part of the parameter description. \nThe description can include paragraph breaks.\n\nThe Parameter keywords can appear in any order in the comment block, but the function or script syntax determines the order in which the parameters \n(and their descriptions) appear in help topic. To change the order, change the syntax.\n\n.PARAMETER filePath\nProvide a PARAMETER section for each parameter that your script or function accepts.\n\n.EXAMPLE\nA sample command that uses the function or script, optionally followed by sample output and a description. Repeat this keyword for each example. If you have multiple examples,\nthere is no need to number them. PowerShell will number the examples in help text.\n\n.EXAMPLE\nThis example will be labeled \"EXAMPLE 2\" when help is displayed to the user.\n#>\n\nconfiguration HelpSample1\n{\n    param([string]$computername,[string]$filePath)\n    File f\n    {\n        Contents=\"Hello World\"\n        DestinationPath = \"c:\\Destination.txt\"\n    }\n}\n```\n\n## Viewing configuration help\n\nTo view the help for a configuration, use the **Get-Help** cmdlet with the name of the function, or type the name of the function followed by `-?`. The following is the output\nof the previous function when passed to **Get-Help**:\n\n```powershell\nPS C:\\> Get-Help HelpSample1\n\nNAME\n    HelpSample1\n    \nSYNOPSIS\n    A brief description of the function or script. This keyword can be used only once for each configuration.\n    \n    \nSYNTAX\n    HelpSample1 [[-InstanceName] <String>] [[-DependsOn] <String[]>] [[-OutputPath] <String>] [[-ConfigurationData] <Hashtable>] [[-computername] \n    <String>] [[-filePath] <String>] [<CommonParameters>]\n    \n    \nDESCRIPTION\n    A detailed description of the function or script. This keyword can be used only once for each configuration.\n    \n\nRELATED LINKS\n\nREMARKS\n    To see the examples, type: \"get-help HelpSample1 -examples\".\n    For more information, type: \"get-help HelpSample1 -detailed\".\n    For technical information, type: \"get-help HelpSample1 -full\".\n```\n\n## See Also\n* [DSC Configurations](configurations.md)"}